# JOHN MWENDA KIARA

Phone Number: 0719 512 216 E-**mail:** jmwenda56@gmail.com Date of Birth: 15<sup>th</sup> August 1991

Nationality: Kenyan Marital Status: Single

Github: <a href="https://github.com/johnmwenda">https://github.com/johnmwenda</a>

## **Personal Summary**

A talented Web Developer with a strong academic background in Computer Science and experience in Computer Networks. I have an aptitude of quickly understanding new technologies or frameworks and can get up to speed with new frameworks in a relatively short period of time.

### **Core Skills**

I am proficient in Object oriented PHP, JavaScript and PostgreSQL. For frameworks I am good at Laravel, Wordpress and Angular JS. I also have experience building angular android apps using Ionic

### **Education**

Computer Science (BSc) Second Class Honors Upper Division	Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology	2011 - 2014
Certificate in Business Management(DCM2)	Kenya Institute of Management	2010-2011
KCSE - A plain of 82 points	Meru School	2006 - 2009
KCPE - A-(416 out of 500)	Modern Green Primary School	1998 - 2005

## **Work Experience**

Healthix Solutions Kenya Job Title: <u>Software Developer</u>

October 2016 -March 2017

#### Responsibilities

- Coordinated and led the front end development team
   I was responsible for developing standard coding styles and procedures for the team, for example I researched on the best file structure for our code base, git versioning strategies and system integration
- I was involved in numerous design discussions with the business development manager and other developers.

- Create design and system documentation using flow charts and UML diagrams
- Rapidly develop effective and beautiful User Interfaces using AngularJS, Bootstrap and CSS
- Develop a robust build process to automate common front end tasks such as transpiling ES6 to Javascript, minification, concatenation and also autogeneration of templates and files. This greatly boosted the development time.

CrowdPesa Job Title: <u>Software Developer</u> May - July 2016

## Responsibilities

Create a new hybrid mobile app for the already existing website. This
exposed me to AngularJS and the Ionic mobile framework which is used
in the development process. I was involved in requirements gathering,
design, front end development and backend development. I used Code
Igniter REST API as the backend of the app.

#### Other Responsibilities

- Develop a Phone verification system using PHP. The system allows phone number to be verified by sending a code to the user and if they put the code sent the number is verified.
- Develop a client testimonial slider (module) to be added to the website.
   Used jQuery library

## Adcare Limited Kenya Job Title: <u>Technical Support Engineer</u>

October 2015 - April 2016

#### Responsibilities

- Deployment, implementation and troubleshooting of computer and network operations(WAN/LAN/MPLS)
- Network monitoring, analysis and generation of reports to the clients
- Network security: install firewalls and antivirus at workstations
- Schedule periodic network/PC maintenance and activities
- Applying patches in accordance with company procedures and policies
- Training new support engineers and users on the new applications and the Amadeus network

# Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

February 2013 -April 2013

Job Title: <u>Information Technology Intern</u>

Responsibilities

During the period I underwent a training program called "Endeavor Android Development Training Program" where I learnt Android development and created an app called 'BiasharaTips' as the main project. BiasharaTips is an information app which allows users to easily access precise relevant data concerning every aspect of business such as; how to start a company, writing a business plan etc. and it also has a local database that allows the user to store daily sales and expenses easily on the phone.

I also did networking and Maintenance

## **Professional Development**

- CISCO Certified CCNA 2015
- IBM DB2 Academic Associate Certification August 2014
- Endeavour Mobile Applications Development Program, JKUAT. Android Applications development training. January to April 2014
- Web development technologies e.g. HTML5, PHP, JavaScript, and Content Management Systems such as Joomla and WordPress

## **Own Projects**

- Online Bulk SMS System using PHP and Africastalking API.
- Developed several websites using Joomla/WordPress for different organizations. You can view portfolio here: <a href="http://johnmwenda.github.io">http://johnmwenda.github.io</a>

## Leadership/Hobbies

- Served as a Library Prefect in High School.
- Served as Organizing Secretary for the high school Christian Union
- Part of a Charity group that occasionally visits children's homes, and other charitable events
- Swimming, and also travelling.
- I have a full driving license.

#### Referees

#### 1. Mr. Daniel Munyua

Software Engineer, Renee Media. Phone:

0720203723

Email:

danielmunyua@gmai l.com

## 2. Mrs. Faith M. Gichovi

Dean of Students, St. Mark's Kigari Primary Teachers College

Phone:

0726794052/0733249

552 Email :

fgichovi@yahoo.co.uk

#### 3. Mugambi Felix Mwiti

Web developer, Kenya Tea Development Authority, Box 9821-00100

Nairobi

Phone: +254

721887037

Email: fmugambi@gmail.com